<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ML Basics on ML</title>
    <link>https://tactlabs.github.io/ml-interview-questions/ml-basics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ML Basics on ML</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 19:38:26 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tactlabs.github.io/ml-interview-questions/ml-basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>15 things to avoid</title>
      <link>https://tactlabs.github.io/ml-interview-questions/ml-basics/15_things_to_avoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 19:40:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tactlabs.github.io/ml-interview-questions/ml-basics/15_things_to_avoid/</guid>
      <description>15 Data fallacies to Avoid
The common refrain is: Lies, damned lies, and statistics.
Check out these common data fallacies beautifully illustrated and summarized by Geckoboard.
1. Cherry Picking
Select data that supports your claim, and hide that does not. Always ask: Is it full data? What filters have been applied?
2. Data Dredging
Hiding that correlation is not statistically significant. Instead of defining a hypothesis up front, it is switched after data dredging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Question Set 1</title>
      <link>https://tactlabs.github.io/ml-interview-questions/ml-basics/question_set_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 19:40:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tactlabs.github.io/ml-interview-questions/ml-basics/question_set_1/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning Interview Questions: 4 Categories
We’ve traditionally seen machine learning interview questions pop up in several categories. The first really has to do with the algorithms and theory behind machine learning. You’ll have to show an understanding of how algorithms compare with one another and how to measure their efficacy and accuracy in the right way. The second category has to do with your programming skills and your ability to execute on top of those algorithms and the theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Question Set 2</title>
      <link>https://tactlabs.github.io/ml-interview-questions/ml-basics/question_set_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 19:40:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tactlabs.github.io/ml-interview-questions/ml-basics/question_set_2/</guid>
      <description>Question Set 2
1. What Are the Different Types of Machine Learning?
There are three types of machine learning:
Supervised Learning
In supervised machine learning, a model makes predictions or decisions based on past or labeled data. Labeled data refers to sets of data that are given tags or labels, and thus made more meaningful.
Unsupervised Learning
In unsupervised learning, we don&amp;rsquo;t have labeled data. A model can identify patterns, anomalies, and relationships in the input data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Question Set 3</title>
      <link>https://tactlabs.github.io/ml-interview-questions/ml-basics/question_set_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 19:40:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tactlabs.github.io/ml-interview-questions/ml-basics/question_set_3/</guid>
      <description>1. What are the types of Machine Learning?
In all the ML Interview Questions that we would be going to discuss, this is one of the most basic question. So, basically, there are three types of Machine Learning techniques: Supervised Learning: In this type of the Machine Learning technique, machines learn under the supervision of labeled data. There is a training dataset on which the machine is trained, and it gives the output according to its training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Question Set 4</title>
      <link>https://tactlabs.github.io/ml-interview-questions/ml-basics/question_set_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 19:40:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tactlabs.github.io/ml-interview-questions/ml-basics/question_set_4/</guid>
      <description>Question Set 4
1. Explain the terms Artificial Intelligence (AI), Machine Learning (ML and Deep Learning?
Artificial Intelligence (AI) is the domain of producing intelligent machines. ML refers to systems that can assimilate from experience (training data) and Deep Learning (DL) states to systems that learn from experience on large data sets. ML can be considered as a subset of AI. Deep Learning (DL) is ML but useful to large data sets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
